Guide to the Martin I. J. Griffin, Jr. Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Martin I. J. Griffin, Jr., papers
1883-1988
1955-1988
MS 1565
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.75
(15 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, teaching materials, and subject files documenting the personal and professional life of Martin I. J. Griffin, Jr.
Griffin, Martin I. J. (Martin Ignatius Joseph), 1933-1988
Conditions Governing Access
Student recommendations in box 14 are restricted until January 1, 2045 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Barbara Farrell, 1998; John W. Alexander, Jr., 2010.
Biographical / Historical
Martin Ignatius Joseph Griffin, Jr. was born in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania on November 13, 1933. He graduated from St. Petersburg High School in St. Petersburg, Florida in 1951, and then attended the University of Pennsylvania. There he was a member of Phi Beta Kappa and editor of The Daily Pennsylvanian. In 1955 he received a B.A. with distinction in European history. Griffin then entered Yale University, where he received the degrees of M.A. in 1956 and Ph.D. in 1963. During his years at Yale he was a freshman counselor and a Fulbright Scholar at the University of London. From 1959 to 1972 he taught courses on British history in Yale College. A devout Catholic, his primary academic interest was the history of Catholic apologetics in Britain. For nearly all of his Yale career he was a resident fellow at Saybrook College, where he was dean from 1968 to 1971. From then until 1973 Griffin was assistant dean of Yale College. In 1973 he became associate dean of Yale College, and in 1976 he took on additional responsibility as dean of undergraduate studies. At various times he served as director of undergraduate studies for the history department and chairman of the Yale College executive committee. Griffin was quite popular with Yale students and would frequently take them to Mory's restaurant, and was active in the life of Saybrook College. Griffin, who never married, died in 1988.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, writings, teaching materials, and subject files documenting the personal and professional life of Martin I. J. Griffin, Jr.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series and one addition: Correspondence, 1954-1988. Teaching, 1959-1972. Writings, 1916-1987. Subject Files and Photograph, 1883-1987. Additional material includes correspodence and postcards arranged in chronological order.
Griffin, Martin I. J. (Martin Ignatius Joseph), 1933-1988; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students
- Correspondence, 1954-1988; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  The series is arranged in alphabetical order by last name of correspondent, and includes Griffin's professional and personal correspondence. Correspondence with unidentified persons is arranged at the end of the series in alphabetical order by first name of the correspondent.
  - A (general), 1957-1960, 1979-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adams, Jeremy and Bonnie, 1969-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Akenson, Jon, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Albert, Sister Mary, S.S.J., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alexander, John C.T., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alexander, John W. Jr. ["Johannes"], 1956- 1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ameling, Ann, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Angell, Katherine ["Kay"], 1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arader, Alexander J., 1971-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Archibald, Brian and Daphne, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Archibald, Elizabeth, 1978-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Atherton, Herb M., 1971, 1981-1986, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Atkin, Donald, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Atkins, Elisha and Libby, 1967, 1976-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Avery, Mike, 1965, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - B (general), 1958-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Babcock, Charles L., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bainton, Roland, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Barnett, Roger L., 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Barrett, John, 1958-1959, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baumer, F.L., 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Beals, Mrs. Robert, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bekenstein, Josh, 1978-1985, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bemis, Charles, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bemis, Christopher, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bennett, G.V., 1959, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Berry, Charlie, 1970-1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bettis, David, 1976-1979, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Biddle, Mark H. And Melinda, 1974-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Bierce, Bill, 1955- 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Block, Douglas, 1970-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bohan, Peter, Fran, and Bill, 1961-1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Borg, Dan, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Boxer, Charles, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Brackman, Allan, 1959-1964 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bruack, Darryl, 1973, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bruner, Robert F., 1972-1977 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Bruwes, S., 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Burton, David H., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - C (general), 1956-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Campbell, Andrew, 1983-1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Campbell, Duncan, 1966-1971, 1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Campbell, Gertrude, Christopher, and Ralph, 1966, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Campbell, Jim, 1966, 1978-1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Carter, Marshall, 1976-1987 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Case, David Knowlton, 1958-1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Casey, Frederick H., 1956-1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Castillo, Justin, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Cates, Willard Jr. ["Ward"], 1965-1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Chip, Bill, 1972, 1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Chwe, Myron, 1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Crawford, Tom, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Cronk, Richard, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Curran, Charles, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Curtis, Jane, 1970, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Curtis, Lewis P., 1959, 1965, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - D (general), 1956-1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Dauppe, Tessa, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Denzel, Michael, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - DePillis, M., 1961 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Devlin, Michael, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Dietrich, Rick, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Dodge, William, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Dorsey, Woody, undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Dougherty, Dr. John Stewart, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Dougherty, Michael Stewart, 1969, 1972, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Duggan, Ben, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - E (general), 1955-1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Engler, Alan, 1975-1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Ettinger, John R., 1974-1975, 1979, undated (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Ewing, Richard, 1973-1974, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - F (general), 1957-1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Faggart, Dr. Harold L., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Faloon, Kelly, 1972-1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Farman, Ed, 1960-1961, undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Feldman, Sander, 1956-1961, 1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Ferguson, Alan D., 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Fitzherberry, Anthony, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Fletcher, Frank Barron, III, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Folson, James K., 1968, 1982, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Fossier, Richard ["Rick"], 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Fowler, W.B., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Fox, Kevin, 1985-1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Fox, Robert and Loretta, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Fragner, Matthew C., 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Frink, Tony, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - G (general), 1955-1987 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Galambas, Skip, Marty, and Louis, 1959, 1979, undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Gallagher, Jack, undated (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Gariepy, Rev. Thomas, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Garside, C. Jr., 1959-1965, 1986, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Ghriskey, Susan, undated (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Giamatti, A. Bartlett, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Giff, Jerry, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Girdwood, Joseph, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Givan, Christopher ["Kit"], 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Godfrey, Pete, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Glenday, Ian, 1971-1982 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Goldstein, Melvin, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Goodyear, Julia, undated (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Goodyear, Sam, 1966, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Graves, Nielson [Nellie], 1976-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Gray, Gordon, 1977-1982, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Greaves, Robert W., 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Griffin, Mrs. William ["Grandma"], 1959-1960, undated (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Griggs, Timothy S., 1985, undated (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Grimes, George, 1976, 1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Grimsland, Bob, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Gross, James, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Grosvenor, Edwin S., 1975-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - H (general), 1968-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Hahn, Emily, 1973-1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Hall, Jay, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Haun, Eugene, 1956-1963, 1972, 1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Haverly, John and Agnes, 1958-1960 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Hayes, Helen, 1983-1985, undated (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Henning, Basil D. ["Duke"] and Alison P., 1958-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 117-118)
  - Hines, David, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Holden, Reuben A., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Holland, Walter, 1980-1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Holsenbeck, Diane, Penn, and Alexander, 1968-1987, undated (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Horton, Keith, 1955- 1980, undated (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Huelin, Gordon, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Hunsicker John F. Jr., undated (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Hunter, Jonathan, 1982-1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Hunter, William, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Hyde, Andrea and Peggy, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Hyde, Jim, 1967-1969, 1981-1983, undated (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - I (general), 1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - J (general), 1958-1969 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Jacobson, Carl, 1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - James, David L., 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - K (general), 1956-1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Kartus, Jesse, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Kase, Steve, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Kaufman, Jonathan, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Kelly, Christopher ["Chip"], 1980-1987 (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - Kelly, Jim, 1977-1978, undated (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - Kertman, Paul, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Kidney, Michael, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Kierkegaard, J.M., 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - Kinlochi, Hector, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 143)
  - Kneafrey, Barry, 1966-1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Knowles, James B., 1969, undated (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Kuehn, Robert, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Kugelmann, Tom and Mrs. B., 1959 (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - L (general), 1959-1970, 1979-1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 148)
  - Leavy, Stanley A., 1969-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 149)
  - Lee, Richard C., 1979, undated (Box 4, Folder 150)
  - Leluyn, Arthur, 1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Lilley, Bill, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Lincoln, Elaine, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Logan, John, 1970, undated (Box 4, Folder 154)
  - Lopez, Robert, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Lovaas, Mark, 1975-1979, undated (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - Luchka, Hansi, 1966, 1969, undated (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - Ludington, Evelyn, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Luoto, Mark, 1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Lyle, Anthony A., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - M (general), 1956-1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - Macaulay, A.J., undated (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - Maccioni, Al, 1973-1980, undated (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - MacIsaac, David, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - MacMillan, Sandy, 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - McClure, Mary, undated (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - McConnell, Dorsey, 1975-1986 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - McDermott, William, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - McLeod, Christopher ["Toby"], 1973-1980, undated (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - McNally, Ed, 1977-1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - Mace and Chain, undated (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - Magee, Joseph G., Jr., 1955-1960 (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Mali, Peter, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 173)
  - Mangas, Cloyce Leland ["Lee"], 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - Mayo, Mary Irwin, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Meadow, Ginnie, 1986, 1972, undated (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - Meehan, Ann [cousin], undated (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - Meehan, Mary Margaret ["Missy" -- cousin], 1958-1961, 1985, undated (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - Meehan, William, Sue, and Mary, 1958-1987, undated (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - Meisner, Jon, 1977-1980, undated (Box 5, Folder 180)
  - Metraux, Guido, 1964-1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 181)
  - Metzger, Robert, 1977, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 182)
  - Meyer, Daniel, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - Meyer, Jeffrey, 1982-1987 (Box 5, Folder 184)
  - Meyer, Tory, 1983-1987, undated (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - Miles, Michael, 1983-1987 (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - Milch, Randal S. ["Randy"], 1978-1980, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 187)
  - Milet, Randy, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 188)
  - Miller, Dave, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 189)
  - Miller, Oliver, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 190)
  - Minno, Jeremy, undated (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - Mintz, Sid and Jackie, 1971-1972, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Mis, Ronald, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - Monahan, William, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - Montgomery, Susie B., undated (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Moore, J.D., 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Morley, Jefferson M., 1979-1985 (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Muffly, Robert, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Murphy, Brian, 1975-1987 (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Murphy, James Peter, Barbara, and Brian, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Murphy, Michael, 1977-1983 (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - Murray, Williamson ["Wick"], 1977-1980, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - N (general), 1955-1986, undated (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - Nightingale, Neville G., 1960 (Box 5, Folder 204)
  - Noble, David, 1961-1962, 1975-1983 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - Nuland, Drew, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - O (general), 1956-1960, 1975, 1983-1987, undated (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - O'Brien, Rose [aunt], 1955, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - Olivarius, Ann, 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - Ornston, Darius ["Darry"], 1957-1981 (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - P (general), 1958-1987, undated (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - Park, Darregh A., III, 1961-1963, undated (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - Penn, Estelle [Mrs. George], 1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - Philbin, Jim, 1977-1985 (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - Philip, Peter S., 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - Pierce, Erin, 1960, 1977-1986, undated (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - Pierce, Ian [Smith], 1968-1983 (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - Pierce, Kelly [nephew], 1969-1985, undated (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - Pierce, Patricia, 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 219)
  - Pierson, George W., 1987 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - Pitti, Robert H., 1956-1960, undated (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - Porter, Robert, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - Porter, Sandra and Jack, 1956-1961, 1981-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 223)
  - Post, Herschel E., 1960, undated (Box 6, Folder 224)
  - Quinn, George, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 225)
  - R (general), 1955-1965, 1972-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 226)
  - Rappaport, Aaron, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 227)
  - Rasmussen, K., 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 228)
  - Ratcliffe, Alan, 1960-1961 (Box 6, Folder 229)
  - Reeve, Brock, 1975-1977, 1985, undated (Box 6, Folder 230)
  - Reeve, Helen and Franklin, 1972-1979, 1983, undated (Box 6, Folder 231)
  - Reider, Stuart E., 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 232)
  - Resnick, Jessica [Mrs. Jerome], 1981-1982, 1986, undated (Box 6, Folder 233)
  - Rice, Susan and Duncan, 1964, 1971-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 234)
  - Riley, Auntie, 1966, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 235)
  - Rizopoulos, N.X., 1966, 1971, 1981-1983, undated (Box 6, Folder 236)
  - Roberts, Stone, 1973, 1977, undated (Box 6, Folder 237)
  - Roberts, Tony and Angela, 1964-1966, 1975, undated (Box 6, Folder 238)
  - Rogers, Dulcy, 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 239)
  - Rogers, Mary, 1962, undated (Box 6, Folder 240)
  - Roosevelt, Ens. Franklin D. III, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 241)
  - Rossiter, Edward V.W. [Ned], 1986, undated (Box 6, Folder 242)
  - Rostow, Nick [Gene and Edna], 1974, 1977, 1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 243)
  - Rowe, Daniel S., 1975-1985 (Box 6, Folder 244)
  - Russell, Richard R., 1979-1986 (Box 6, Folder 245)
  - S (general), 1955-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 246)
  - Saalbach, Raymond C., 1955-1964 (Box 6, Folder 247)
  - Sachs, Ebba and Herbert, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 248)
  - Sager, John, 1975-1980 (Box 6, Folder 249)
  - Saro, Anthony ["Tony"], 1985-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 250)
  - Sawyer, Leslie, 1973-1979 (Box 6, Folder 251)
  - Schmidt, Benno C., Jr., 1986 (Box 6, Folder 252)
  - Schned, Eric, 1971-1972, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 253)
  - Schonfeld, Norman J., 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 254)
  - Sellers, Lib [Mrs. John B.], 1964-1968 (Box 6, Folder 255)
  - Shank, Richard R., 1961 (Box 6, Folder 256)
  - Sherman, Mike, 1972-1975, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 257)
  - Sloan, Nick, undated (Box 6, Folder 258)
  - Smith, Don ["D.A"], 1968-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 259)
  - Spadafora, David, 1982-1985 (Box 6, Folder 260)
  - Sprunt, G.L., 1959-1964 (Box 6, Folder 261)
  - Stebbins, Charles, 1977-1980, 1985, undated (Box 6, Folder 262)
  - Sterling, Whit, 1975--1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 263)
  - Stevens, David, 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 264)
  - Stevens, Paul Schott, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 265)
  - Stewart, Mrs. Henry [Aunt Margaret, Aunt Peggy], 1955-1961 (Box 6, Folder 266)
  - Stillman, Stanley, 1961, 1968, 1979-1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - Stock, Cathy, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 268)
  - Stone, Guy, 1975-1976, 1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 269)
  - Sunberg, Randy, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - Swartz, Bruce, 1975-1976, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 271)
  - Swett, Trevor [Ted"] and Ann, 1978-1985 (Box 7, Folder 272)
  - T (general), 1959-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 273)
  - Taliaferro, Fanny, 1956-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 274)
  - Tate, Elizabeth ["Liz"], 1982-1986 (Box 7, Folder 275)
  - Teahan, Vincent, 1970-1979, 1986-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 276)
  - Teller, Raymond J., 1953 (Box 7, Folder 277)
  - Tonkinson, John and Christine, 1970, 1984-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 278)
  - Toomey, Mike, 1964, undated (Box 7, Folder 279)
  - U (general), 1962, 1974, 1981, 1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 280)
  - V (general), 1972, 1981-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 281)
  - Vincent, R.K. ["Chip"], 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 282)
  - von Isakovics, Alois, 1962-1967, undated (Box 7, Folder 283)
  - W (general), 1959, 1966-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 284)
  - Wagner, Roger, 1977-1981, undated (Box 7, Folder 285)
  - Walter, Heinrich R., 1955 (Box 7, Folder 286)
  - Wanders, David G., 1979-1986 (Box 7, Folder 287)
  - Wang, KeGang, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 288)
  - Ward, Robert, 1979-1986 (Box 7, Folder 289)
  - Warner, Alden, 1979-1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 290)
  - Weber, Rev. Francis J., 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 291)
  - Weinberg, Paul, 1959-1960, undated (Box 7, Folder 292)
  - Westendorff, David G., 1974-1987, undated (Box 7, Folder 293)
  - Whiteman, Harold B., 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 294)
  - Whitney, Courtney, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 295)
  - Wilder, Isabel and Thornton Niven, 1976-1979 (Box 7, Folder 296)
  - Wilder, Tappan ["Tappy"] and Robin, 1975, 1978-1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 297)
  - Wilkinson, John A., 1986 (Box 7, Folder 298)
  - Williams, David, 1966, 1969, 1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 299)
  - Willits, Joseph H., 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 300)
  - Winks, Robin, 1963, 1986, undated (Box 7, Folder 301)
  - Wofford, Danny, 1975-1983, undated (Box 7, Folder 302)
  - Worth, Alexander ["Alexi"], 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 303)
  - Wright, Marcia, 1958-1962 (Box 7, Folder 304)
  - Y (general), 1962, 1965, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 305)
  - Z (general), 1961, 1963, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 306)
  - Zimmerman, Ann, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 307)
  - Correspondence of others, 1957-1967 (Box 7, Folder 308)
  - Unidentified, 1954-1987, undated (Box 8, Folder 309-315)
- Teaching, 1959-1972; Series II
  The series is divided into four sections: course material, student recommendations, students' writings, and Yale University Department of History. The course material section includes syllabi, exams, handouts and reading lists, and lectures for the courses Griffin taught. The materials are arranged by course; lectures not assigned to a course are arranged alphabetically. The students' writings section contains papers students wrote for Griffin's classes. The Yale University Department of History section includes internal reports, statistics, and a letter to a student regarding his overdue papers for a course taught by Griffin.
  - Course materials
    - History 21a [History of Britain until 1603]
      - Syllabi, 1959-1969 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Exams, 1959-1968, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Lectures
        - Pre-Norman Britain, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Battle of Hastings, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Transformation of England, 1066-1154, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - Normanization of the church, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
        - Henry II (1154-1189): the restoration of royal supremacy, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Church and state from Anselm to Becket, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
        - The reign of King John, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - Henry III (1216-1272): "Le Re della simplice vita", undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
        - The medieval world outlook, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
        - Thirteenth century England: towns, friars, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - The English Justinian: Edward I (1272-1307), undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
        - Wales, Scotland, and the Hundred Years' War, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
        - The fourteenth century, 1307-1399: an age of unrest, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
        - The fourteenth-century church, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
        - Lancaster and York, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
        - The "Dull Tudor": Henry VII (1485-, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
        - The Henrician revolution, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
        - The reign of the "Young Josiah": Edward VI, 1547-1553, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
        - The failure of reaction: Mary I (1553-1558), undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
        - The Elizabethan settlement in religion (I), undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
        - The Elizabethan settlement in religion (II), undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
        - "For Christ, and England's peerless Queen": the struggle with Spain, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
        - Life in Elizabethan England, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
        - The Elizabethan Constitution, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - History 21b [History of England, 1603-1964]
      - Syllabi, 1960-1970, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
      - Exams, 1960-1970, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - Lectures
        - "The wisest fool in Christendom", undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
        - Charles I, Buckingham, and Laud, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
        - Civil war and interregnum, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
        - The long parliament and reform, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
        - The long parliament and revolution, undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
        - Happy restoration in church and state, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
        - The Whig offensive and Tory revenge, undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
        - The Glorious revolution, undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
        - Completion of the glorious revolution, undated (Box 10, Folder 38)